Yifeng Wang

i@ewind.us | github.com/doodlewind | twitter@ewind1994

SUMMARY

As a Web developer and tech influencer, I'm experienced in building various kinds of Web-based productivity tools, designing Web editor frameworks, diving into Web specs, giving talks on tech conferences like QCon+, GMTC and D2, contributing to OSS projects and writing tech blogs. I'm also the translator of JavaScript: the First 20 Years (Chinese version).

WORK EXPERIENCE

Xiamen, China; Gaoding Inc., Senior Web developer (2018/01 - Present) Leading the graphics design editor team, developed features including real-time collaboration, 3D text (with custom WebGL renderer) and TDD framework. Built Skia-based canvas runtimes on iOS/Android with QuickJS and Dart VM (blog). Led the business partnership with Photopea editor, got exclusive Chinese license.

Xiamen, China; Meituan-Dianping Inc., Web developer (2017/05 - 2018/01) Creator of Citadel editor, the enterprise wiki editor for Meituan-Dianping. Got 20+PR merged into the editor framework (<u>Slate</u>, 23.5k star) upstream.

Hefei, China; iFlytek Co., Ltd., Web developer (2016/07 - 2017/05) Built Web admin for iFlytek's speech recognition SDK. First to introduce Webpack-based tech stack into projects. Awarded Newcomer of the Year.

SKILLS

Familiar with a particular subset of JavaScript, TypeScript, Rust, and C/C++. Experienced in implementing HTML5 Canvas spec, customizing WebGL pipeline, building JavaScript runtime and maintaining Web editor frameworks. Average understanding of Web UI frameworks (Vue, React, etc.).

MISCELLANEOUS

Patents licensed (CN): ZL 2019 1 0846361.0 (An Approach Viewing 3D Text), ZL 2018 1 1336345.9 (An Approach Adjusting Font Effect)

Non-trivial contributions to OSS projects: <u>Slate</u> (React-based rich text editing framework), <u>Yjs</u> (CRDT library for shared editing), <u>skr-canvas</u> (HTML5 Canvas implementation for Node.js) and <u>Txiki</u> (JavaScript runtime based on QuickJS).

Novel personal projects: A custom React <u>renderer</u> targeting SSD1306 OLED chip; a Mocha (first JavaScript engine written in 1995) <u>port</u> to WASM; QuickJS engine ports for MIPS <u>handheld game console</u> and <u>Sony PSP</u>; a hash-based <u>history state manager</u>, a Rubik's Cube <u>renderer and solver</u> within 10KB; a Chip-8 <u>emulator</u> for Web.

EDUCATION

University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China B.S. Information Security, 2016